<resources>
    <string name="app_name">OBWheels</string>
    <!--
    <string name="title_home">Home</string>
    <string name="title_dashboard">Dashboard</string>
    <string name="title_notifications">Notifications</string>
    <string name="title_aboutus">About Us</string>
    -->

    <string name="title_home">OB Wheels</string>
    <string name="title_disclaimer">Disclaimer</string>
    <string name="title_aboutApp">About App</string>
    <string name="title_ref">References</string>
    <string name="title_moreApps">More Apps</string>
    <string name="disclaimer_text">"Accuracy &amp; Disclaimer\n\nCalendar:  The calendar is accurate even in leap years.  But you have to know how to apply this information to individual patient care and make adjustments as clinically appropriate.\n\nOB wheel:  Most cardboard wheels have some inaccuracy.  I have found this wheel to be geometrically and clinically accurate (except for leap years as there is no adjustment for a February with 29 days).  However, if you are uncertain about the results, feel free to double-check on the calendar calculator.  It is based upon your discretion and clinical judgement whether and how to use the cycle length adjustment or stick with the standard 28 day cycle.\n\nScheme for reconciling LMP &amp; Sono EDD's:  there are several schemes in clinical use for setting a final due date from the LMP and Sono.  I am unaware of evidence which proves any one scheme superior to another.  I have presented the ACOG scheme because we use it in our practice.  If you prefer another scheme, you may use your discretion and use it.\n\nIf you suspect there is an inaccuracy in any of the tools in this app, please contact me as soon as possible.\n\nFinally, like all my apps, this tool provides information about care of patients in general.  But it may not provide guidance on the single unique patient before you this moment.  This tool is no substitute for training, experience, and judgment.  You must already know all about setting due dates and gestational ages, this tool merely puts assistance at your fingertips.  Individualize your care to your patient, your local standards, your local resources, and new information as it comes out.\n"</string>
    <string name="aboutapp_text">"Development of App\n\nWritten to put due date calculator tools and information about setting the due date in the hands of clinicians, students, and residents at the point of care.\n\nContent+Design:\n  Joshua Steinberg MD,\n\tUHS Wilson Family Practice Residency,\n\tBinghamton, NY\n\nProgrammer:\n  Harshad C. Loya,\n\tMS - Computer Science,\n\tSUNY - Binghamton,\n\tBinghamton, NY\n\n\nFeedback:\njds.pocapps@gmail.com or hloya1@binghamton.edu\nPlatform: Android 4.0.3 and later\nVersion: 1.0\nCopyright: March, 2017"</string>
    <string name="ref_text">"References\n\nMethod for Estimating Due Date.\nAmerican College of Obstetricians and Gynecologists (ACOG).  Committee Opinion Number 611.  Obst Gyn vol. 124, no. 4, October, 2014.\n\nBennett KA, et. al. First trimester ultrasound screening is effective in reducing postterm labor induction rates: a randomized controlled trial. Am J Obst Gyn 2004;190:1077–81.\n\nWhitworth M, et. al. Ultrasound for fetal assessment in early pregnancy. Cochrane Database of Systematic Reviews 2010, Issue 4. Art. No.: CD007058.\n\nWegienka G, Baird DD. A comparison of recalled date of last menstrual period with prospectively recorded dates. J Womens Health 2005;14:248–52."</string>


</resources>
